you like that one
you like that little drop shot yeah
well first of all you try to hit a
little too hard sometimes but what can
really help you is
feeling the ball a little more like feel
overall i'm going to show you today some
exercises
where you can improve your feel you know
what i mean by feel feel is basically
like if you're
feeling the ball with your hand so
feeling the ball with the strings
hitting the ball
a little bit softer it's really
important in the beginning because
you need to be able to control the ball
before you ever start thinking about
power because sometimes in your forehand
i think you try to hit a little too hard
it's a little too wild well you know the
feel can help you tremendously to
get control over the ball and this is
something you can do actually at home
i'm giving you homework today okay you
want to get homework
all right so here we're going to do some
exercises we've never actually done this
we should have done this in our first
lesson
and we kind of skipped over it so you
take a ball and go to continental grip
okay and now just take the racket like
this put your palm up to the sky
and bounce it on your strings like 10
times
so you can already probably do this nice
not too high not too high soft soft
soft contact oh you got ten you got ten
okay good enough we're going to the next
thing
okay what's the next thing now
you keep going it's fun right
all right now the next thing you go down
to the ground
like this 10 times you see this to the
ground
now watch the ball it's harder
you're doing good though you're doing
good
nice all right so this is something you
can do
there's like a warm up before your
practice sessions get your feel going
and now look continental grip you're
going to use both sides of the racket
this is going to be a little trickier
watch
you see this all right try it out
come on be ready always be ready
continental grip continental grip
that's forehand grip yes remember
continental or as you call it
international grip
oh yeah there it is and now you turn the
palm up
okay yep and i'll turn the racket around
there you go wow
you got good hands
okay you see it's a little trickier
right yeah try one more time
good it's five six seven eight
nine ten eleven twelve thirteen fourteen
nice job all right now the next one is
very important in in learning feel is
how to pick up the ball
how do you pick up a ball from the
ground let me see here's a here's a ball
you're playing with someone you're
picking this ball up let me see how do
you pick it up
well i usually do that you're going like
that okay you're not allowed anymore to
pick it up like that none anymore this
is
from now on illegal here's what you're
going to do there's three methods okay
this one you already know there you go
that's one way
all right another way is look you go
like this with the racket
over the ball and you pick it up like
that i think it's such a chore to do
that
not at all it's much easier i never pick
up the ball with my hand
like you just ruined the racket not at
all watch i'm not gonna i'm not gonna
touch the racket at all you see all
right if you're worried about the racket
on this one i got another one for you
here you can pick up the ball by
bouncing it very hard on the ball twice
very hard and fast like pop up
and then one time long so two small ones
pop-up and then one long one watch you
see that
watch it again it's so much easier to
just pick it up you see not at all i'm
telling you
here we go okay let me see
do it again this one is hard come on try
to learn it
remember you need one like stronger
longer hit to make the ball pop up off
the ground
there you go wow you're learning really
fast all right now this one's gonna be
i think this is the easiest okay you can
do that one i do that one too sometimes
the next one's gonna be super important
because you're gonna learn
a real feel you're gonna throw the ball
up into the air and you're gonna catch
it on your strings like this without it
bouncing okay
the way you're gonna do it as the ball
is falling your racket needs to go in
the same direction
and now the ball should stay on your
strings without it bouncing off like
that
continental grip throw it in the air
throw it into the air
no not with the back inside with the
forehand side yeah no you're going to
throw it with your hand
look you throw with your hand and then
you catch it like that
the toss right let's see it again
try another time
you almost had it on that one do it
again
you put the strings in the vicinity of
the ball and you simply
continue going down like that
wow that was impressive now let's do it
one
you almost did it two times in a row all
right let's give me the ball
and let's do it now a little bit more
difficult i'm gonna throw the ball
towards you and do the same thing now
the ball is flying that way
your racket needs to go in this
direction of the ball it needs to go
like that here let me show you throw me
a ball
with your hand throw it this way see i
go like that and catch it
basically going backwards with the
racket here try it out
oh my goodness wow you have unbelievable
feel
that was impressive now if you're really
bored at home you got nothing to do
yeah you can do this stuff at home but
make sure maybe you use a softer ball so
you don't break anything okay now we're
going to actually hit the ball
and incorporate feel into the hit so go
ahead and stand there on the service
line
all right anna so now i'm going to feed
you the ball you're going to tap it to
yourself
and then hit it back over to my side
here we go you tap
and hit go good
wow you're really good at this
and now we can also turn this into a
game where we play out points okay
in the service box we can play out
points like that so if you're ever
playing with someone you can make this
into a little mini tennis game
tap go
[Music]
nice anna come on
good anna why are you the only one
running
why don't you make me run
you're playing everything right at me
oh that's it come on go go go
go go so see that's a fun little game
that can help you improve your feel
because
antenna is just as important as it is to
hit the ball hard later on when you get
really good
it's also very important to learn how to
hit the ball soft and play the ball very
gently okay oh and i want you standing
really close to the net over on the
other side
right there maybe back up a couple of
steps and now let's try to keep the ball
in play
your objective is to hit it as close to
the net as possible
and you can do it in your forehand grip
with a forehand
doing your forehand grip to me we're
going to keep it in play
you should still try to do a regular
swing with your regular swing you have a
little bit more feel
and face me more you two sideways face
me more this way
there you go come closer come a little
closer do your regular forehand and hit
it very gently
close to the net you can even use top
spin there you go
forehand only four forehand only come on
you can do it
nice move your feet come on stay on your
toes good
look at this a little bit softer you're
hitting too hard
you see anna you're overheating a little
bit so you're hitting the ball
a little bit too strong okay slow it
down hit it very gently
still too hard hit it softer
go again
come on softer that was the best one
nice
nice there we go beautiful
that is excellent rally
nice job
there it is come on no but sienna what's
happening now is you you couldn't really
do it in the beginning but then you kind
of figured it out and you started
developing
feel for this particular thing that we
were
it feels like doing oh you like it yeah
and it's also
very it's not so easy to hit the ball so
soft you know because sometimes we have
this
instinct to smack the ball really hard
so you have to really train yourself to
have this
soft hands of course perfect partners
to practice it with my son and yeah eric
a friend of mine absolutely
friend he's like
oh really he's like this so when i
played with him he's actually playing so
gently oh i can always hit his balls
right now he's not a player but that's
the whole thing about you playing with
other people you need to
learn to rally and the most important
thing is control
because if you hit it hard you're not
going to get any rallies you guys are
not going to have
fun playing with each other so control
is not the utmost importance that's the
most important thing in tennis
and the power comes very gradually
because as you get more balls in play
your
confidence will grow and you will trust
that you can hit it harder without
missing it
and this feel stuff that we're doing it
can also help you with that another
thing that's very difficult in tennis is
when you have to run really fast
and then do something very soft with
your hands so the combination of having
a lot of intensity and running super
fast but then also having soft hands uh
that's what we're going to practice now
so i want you standing on the service
line
and i'm going to feed you a ball that's
going to bounce very close to the net
you're going to run super fast get it
off of one bounce and then gently
tap it over just like we did on that
other drill you want to get the ball as
close
to the net as possible on my side okay
all right ready
and go come on go go go go go
it's gonna be very short so you have to
run run your fastest okay
go and gently nice job
now you can even if you want you can try
to get the ball in my basket right here
okay
and run past almost had it
it's a little bit too much there you
gave it too much you overcooked it back
up
all the way no cheating please and get
up come
it's a little bit too much ready come
on i love that one beautiful job
what do you think the feel is worse the
forehand or the backhand
backhand now you know why because you're
using two hands so with two hands the
feel is a little bit more difficult
if you're using one hand it will be
easier so if you want you can actually
use only one hand on this drill
on the backhand you don't really need
two hands on the racket all it again
just gently
don't shovel the ball though don't go
like this look
gently push the ball okay gently push it
yes beautiful and another one come on
anna
come on get in the basket and one more
backhand come on all yours
that counts that counts it touch the
basket very good all right come on up i
got one more for you
this one is going to be similar to the
one we just did but you're going to be
moving laterally so i'm going to push
you from side to side
and you're going to run fast to get to
the balls but you're also going to be
very gentle and
and tap it over get it very close to the
net on my side all right ready and go
come on
very gentle good backhand
shovel it come on forehand good
backhand gently push good poor hand
all right backhand come come come
more gentle come on and backhand side go
on
very nice forehand side come
very nice and backhand side come on
and give me last one match point right
here fantastic job all right you're
already playing with feel
good job